Guide to the Phillip Lopate Papers YCAL MSS 1083
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Teaching Materials, 1968–1975; 4; 2.25 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
  Organized into three subseries: Educational correspondence, student responses to and from Lopate, Student artwork and comic book drafts, and Teaching diaries, students. Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Educational correspondence, student responses to and from Lopate
    - Letters to Bennington MFA students and student evaluations, undated (Box 73, Folder 721-723)
    - Students' and former students' correspondence and course evaluations, undated (Box 73, Folder 724-726)
    - Students' and former students' correspondence and course evaluations, undated (Box 74, Folder 727-728)
    - Union Graduate School colloquium materials, undated (Box 74, Folder 729)
  - Student artwork and comic book drafts
    - Black Cat PS 75 comic book, final copy, undated (Box 74, Folder 730)
    - PS 75 comic drafts and drawings by students, undated (Box 74, Folder 731-735)
  - Teaching diaries, students
    - Student work, general, undated (Box 75, Folder 736)
    - Teaching diaries, students, general, undated (Box 75, Folder 737)
    - East Harlem youth, undated (Box 75, Folder 738-739)
    - Hofstra University student work, undated (Box 75, Folder 740)
    - Lopate's Central Commercial High School diary, undated (Box 75, Folder 741)
    - Plays, stage, undated (Box 75, Folder 742)
    - PS 75 films, undated (Box 75, Folder 743)
    - PS 75 radio project, undated (Box 76, Folder 744)
    - PS 75 writing, undated (Box 76, Folder 745)
    - Public and community relations, grant proposals, undated (Box 76, Folder 746)
    - Teachers and Writers Central Commercial, undated (Box 76, Folder 747)
    - Teaching diaries and student work-Writers in the Schools program, undated (Box 76, Folder 748)
    - Tonya [Pendleton], undated (Box 76, Folder 749-752)
    - Twin Pines, undated (Box 77, Folder 753)
    - 1973 [notebook] (Box 77, Folder 754)
    - 1977 Diary of Teachers and Writers Collaborative (Box 77, Folder 755)
    - 1987-1979 [teaching journal], 1978–1979 (Box 77, Folder 756)
- Printed Materials, 1963-2015 and undated; 5; 3 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
  This series contains publications authored or edited by Phillip Lopate, publications which feature his writing, and special edition publications and unpublished proofs. Notable serials within Series V include the "Phillip Lopate Issue" of Blue Pig Magazine, circa 1970. Also present are many issues of Teachers and Writers magazine, including its special issues, The Whole World Catalogue, an academic publication for which Lopate sat on the Editorial and Advisory Boards, and wrote featured articles throughout the 1970s.
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Printed materials, clippings, general, undated (Box 78, Folder 757-758)
  - "A Grave for My Eyes" Teachers and Writers Collaborative Supplement, undated (Box 78, Folder 759)
  - Allure, 1993 November (Box 78, Folder 760)
  - Bomb number 124, Summer 2013 (Box 78, Folder 761)
  - Book Forum volume 14, number 2, June-August 2007 (Box 78, Folder 762)
  - Book of Methods for Getting Children Interested in Writing annotated copy, undated (Box 78, Folder 763)
  - Cedar Rock volume 3, number 2, Spring 1978 (Box 78, Folder 764)
  - Columbia College, Spring 2013 (Box 78, Folder 765)
  - Columbia Review contest issue volume 43, number 2, 1963 (Box 78, Folder 766)
  - Columbia Review volume 48, number 2, 1969 (Box 78, Folder 767)
  - Columbia Review volume 49, number 1, 1969 (Box 78, Folder 768)
  - The Common number 2, 2011 (Box 79, Folder 769)
  - Dialog, 1983 June (Box 79, Folder 770)
  - Domestic Crude issue 2, Fall 1982 (Box 79, Folder 771)
  - English Teacher's Companion, 1975 (Box 79, Folder 772)
  - Equal Time, 1972 (Box 79, Folder 773)
  - Etiqueta Negra volume 6, number 52, August-September 2007 (Box 79, Folder 774)
  - Fable Writing: A First Draft of a Curriculum Unit, undated (Box 79, Folder 775)
  - First Issue number 2, Summer-Fall 1968 (Box 79, Folder 776)
  - First Issue number 4, Spring-Summer 1970 (Box 79, Folder 777)
  - First Issue number 9, Fall 1974-Winter 1975 (Box 79, Folder 778)
  - Forum, a publication of the University of Houston, volume 17, number 3 and volume 18, number 1, Summer 1979-Winter 1980 (Box 79, Folder 779)
  - Fourth River issue 9, 2012 (Box 79, Folder 780)
  - Gulf Coast volume 23, issue 2, Summer-Fall 2011 (Box 79, Folder 781)
  - Harper's, 2011 January (Box 79, Folder 782)
  - Harvard Educational Review volume 46, number 2, 1976 May (Box 79, Folder 783)
  - Journal of Education volume 162, number 2, Spring 1980 (Box 79, Folder 784)
  - Liberation volume 18, number 2, September-October 1973 (Box 79, Folder 785)
  - Liberation volume 18, number 8, May-June 1974 (Box 79, Folder 786)
  - Liberation volume 19, number 8, 9, May-June 1974 (Box 79, Folder 787)
  - The Little Magazine volume 7, number 3, Fall 1973 (Box 79, Folder 788)
  - Lost Glove volume 1, number 2, Spring 1980 (Box 79, Folder 789)
  - Marxist Perspectives volume 1, number 2, Summer 1978 (Box 79, Folder 790)
  - The Maverick Poets: An Anthology, 1998 (Box 79, Folder 791)
  - Mother Jones volume 2, number 8, September-October 1977 (Box 79, Folder 792)
  - New Worlds 5, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 793)
  - New York Review volume 58, number 3, 2011 February (Box 79, Folder 794)
  - New York Review volume 62, number 9, 2015 May (Box 79, Folder 795)
  - New York Review volume 62, number 12, 2015 July (Box 79, Folder 795A)
  - New York Review volume 62, number 14, 2015 September (Box 79, Folder 796)
  - New York Review volume 62, number 19, 2015 December (Box 79, Folder 797)
  - New York Times number 2, 1971 March (Box 79, Folder 798)
  - New York Times number 3, Winter 1971 (Box 79, Folder 799)
  - New York Times number 4, Winter 1972-1973 (Box 79, Folder 800)
  - None of the Above, 1976 (Box 80, Folder 801)
  - The Normal School volume 5, issue 2, Fall 2012 (Box 80, Folder 802)
  - The Normal School volume 6, issue 2, Fall 2013 (Box 80, Folder 803)
  - The Normal School volume 7, issue 1, Spring 2014 (Box 80, Folder 804)
  - The Normal School volume 8, issue 1, Spring 2015 (Box 80, Folder 805)
  - The Normal School volume 8, issue 2, Fall 2015 (Box 80, Folder 806)
  - Ode to Susan annotated, 1972 (Box 80, Folder 807)
  - Onyx volume 10, Spring 1975 (Box 80, Folder 808)
  - Pacific Film Archive, October-December 1974 (Box 80, Folder 809)
  - The Paris Review volume 56, Spring 1973 (Box 80, Folder 810)
  - Penumbra number 9, 1971 February (Box 80, Folder 811)
  - Penumbra volume 11, 1972 (Box 80, Folder 812)
  - Pequod volume 2, number 4, 1978 (Box 80, Folder 813)
  - Peter O'Toole number 3, 2007 November (Box 80, Folder 814)
  - Blue Pig number 22, "The Phillip Lopate Issue", undated (Box 80, Folder 815)
  - Ploughshares at Emerson College, volume 38, numbers 2-3, Fall 2012 (Box 80, Folder 816)
  - The Poetry Project newspaper, volume 59, 1978 November (Box 80, Folder 817)
  - The Point Where Teaching and Writing Intersect, 1983 (Box 80, Folder 818)
  - Response: A Contemporary Jewish Review volume 11, number 4, Winter 1978-1979 (Box 80, Folder 819)
  - Response: A Contemporary Jewish Review volume 12, number 4, Spring 1981 (Box 80, Folder 820)
  - Revista de Libros volume 1, number 1, 2008 April (Box 80, Folder 821)
  - Right On, Right On, Right On, undated (Box 80, Folder 822)
  - Roy Rogers, 1970 (Box 80, Folder 823)
  - Salmagundi number 168-169, Fall 2010-Winter 2011 (Box 80, Folder 824)
  - Salmagundi number 185-186, Winter-Spring 2015 (Box 80, Folder 825)
  - Sun volume 4, number 1, Spring 1974 (Box 80, Folder 826)
  - Sun volume 4, number 3, Winter 1979-1980 (Box 80, Folder 827)
  - Sun volume 5, number 1, Winter 1983 (Box 80, Folder 828)
  - Sundial volume 3, number 1, 1969 (Box 80, Folder 829)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 1, issue 1, 1967 September (Box 80, Folder 830)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 1, issue 2, 1967 December (Box 80, Folder 831)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 1, issue 3, 1968 April (Box 80, Folder 832)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 2, issue 1, 1969 April (Box 80, Folder 833)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 3, issue 1, 1970 January (Box 80, Folder 834)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 3, issue 2, 1970 April (Box 81, Folder 835)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 3, issue 3, 1970 October (Box 81, Folder 836)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 3, issue 4, 1971 January (Box 81, Folder 837)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 4, issues 1-2, special issue, May-October 1971 (Box 81, Folder 838)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 4, issue 4, Spring 1973 (Box 81, Folder 839)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 5, issue 1, Fall 1973 (Box 81, Folder 840)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 5, issue 2, Winter 1974 (Box 81, Folder 841)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 5, issue 3, Spring 1974 (Box 81, Folder 842)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 6, issue 1, 1974 (Box 81, Folder 843)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 6, issue 2, Winter 1975 (Box 81, Folder 844)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 6, issue 3, Spring 1975 (Box 81, Folder 845)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 7, issue 1, Fall 1975 (Box 81, Folder 846)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 7, issue 2, Winter 1976 (Box 81, Folder 847)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 7, issue 3, Spring 1976 (Box 81, Folder 848)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 8, issue 1, with supplemental comic Black Cat, Fall 1976 (Box 81, Folder 849)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 8, issue 2, Winter 1977 (Box 81, Folder 850)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 8, issue 3, Spring 1977 (Box 81, Folder 851)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 9, number 1, Fall 1977 (Box 81, Folder 852)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 9, number 2, with supplement, Winter 1978 (Box 81, Folder 853)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 9, number 3, Spring 1978 (Box 81, Folder 854)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 10, number 1, Fall 1978 (Box 81, Folder 855)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 10, number 2, Winter 1979 (Box 81, Folder 856)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 10, number 3, Spring 1979 (Box 81, Folder 857)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 11, number 1, Fall 1979 (Box 81, Folder 858)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 11, number 2, Winter 1979 (Box 81, Folder 859)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 11, number 3, Winter 1979 (Box 81, Folder 860)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 12, number 1, Fall 1980 (Box 81, Folder 861)
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative volume 12, number 2, Winter 1981 (Box 81, Folder 862)
  - Teachers and Writers volume 39, number 1, Fall 2007 (Box 81, Folder 863)
  - Tin House volume 15, number 3, Spring 2014 (Box 81, Folder 864)
  - Telephone number 9, 1973 (Box 81, Folder 865)
  - The Whole World Catalogue, a Teachers and Writers Collaborative special issue, 1972 (Box 81, Folder 866)
  - The Whole World Catalogue, a Teachers and Writers Collaborative special issue, volume 4, issue 3, Summer 1974 (Box 81, Folder 867)
  - The World Trade Center Remembered, 2006 (Box 81, Folder 868)
  - Z number 1, 1973 (Box 81, Folder 869)
- Computer and Audiovisual Media, 1934-2015 and undated; 6; 2 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
  This series includes interviews, lectures, and audio recordings on computer disks, optical media, audiocassettes, videocassettes, and film. It also contains commercially produced optical media.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 82 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information. Box 83 (audiovisual media): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Organized into two subseries: Computer media, and Audiovisual materials
  TypeCollection
  https://preservica.library.yale.edu/explorer/explorer.html#prop:4&0a2fd1dc-03e6-4d63-a05b-ec668f18de8b
  - Computer media and files
    https://preservica.library.yale.edu/explorer/explorer.html#prop:4&56c41d6a-f2d0-4a60-98ac-42cf08f70e2c
    - Computer media, 1934-2013 and undated (Box 82)
      Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Computer files, 2016-ycal-0060-0001
      https://preservica.library.yale.edu/explorer/explorer.html#prop:4&a2073a5e-00ca-45e4-ab97-897b8363e1c9
  - Audiovisual materials
    - Audiocassettes
      - Alumni Voices Phillip Lopate Panelists: Jessica Laimi, Lamia Matta Wednesday, WKCR-FM 89.9, 1987-10-07 (Box 83, Folder 870)
      - Chain novel side one of four National Public Radio, 1987 (Box 83, Folder 871)
      - CM interview, 1982 October (Box 83, Folder 872)
      - Conversation Phillip Lopate Mozart Quartets from Harry Kazan, undated (Box 83, Folder 873)
      - The Corpse's Member BA Sony, undated (Box 83, Folder 874)
      - Huxtable interview part one, undated (Box 83, Folder 875)
      - Huxtable interview part two, undated (Box 83, Folder 876)
      - IRM Phillip Lopate 1.3, 1981-12-29 (Box 83, Folder 877)
      - IRM 2.4, 1981-12-29 (Box 83, Folder 878)
      - Jane Campion Vogue interview, undated (Box 83, Folder 879-880)
      - Lisette Model, Answer Machine, undated (Box 83, Folder 881)
      - Marcel Ophus and Phillip Lopate dub tape one of two, 1992-11-06 (Box 83, Folder 882)
      - Marcel Ophus and Phillip Lopate dub tape two of two, 1992-11-06 (Box 83, Folder 883)
      - The Movies, 2006-11-07 (Box 83, Folder 884)
      - Options in Education #118 Teaching Writing/Options in Ed, Writing Love from Children, undated (Box 83, Folder 885)
      - Paranoia: A Psycho Opera; music by Stephen Eddins, sung text by Phillip Lopate "We Who Are Your Closest Friends," additional spoken text by the cast and composer. Produced by Caterwaul!, the University of Michigan, 1998-03-07 (Box 83, Folder 886)
      - Phillip Lopate and Leonard Lopate at Queens College, An Evening with Phillip Lopate hosted by Leonard Lopate at Queens College Evening Readings, 2000-03-21 (Box 83, Folder 887)
      - Phillip Lopate ML Auditorium, University of Arizona side B, 1991-03-06 (Box 83, Folder 888)
      - Poetry readings, Saint Adrians, undated (Box 83, Folder 889)
      - S7 SEE Luncheon, undated (Box 83, Folder 890)
      - [Side one] Samson and Delilah soundtrack Cyril B De Mille one [Side two] Samson and Delilah soundtrack two, undated (Box 83, Folder 891)
      - Samson and Delilah soundtrack with last ten minutes missing, undated (Box 83, Folder 892)
      - Sontag interview, undated (Box 83, Folder 893)
      - The Three Sisters Who Go to War first improvisation, undated (Box 83, Folder 894)
      - WNYC and Co. 1990 Year in Review #2 with Phillip Lopate, David Shapiro, Anthony DeCurtiss, 1990-12-27 (Box 83, Folder 895)
      - WNYC NYECO "Dumbing Down", 1996-07-15 (Box 83, Folder 896)
      - WNYC NYECO Phillip Lopate, 1996-09-10 (Box 83, Folder 897)
      - WNYC Phillip Lopate, undated (Box 83, Folder 898)
      - WNYC Phillip Lopate American Movie Classics Lenny open phone 62, 2006-03-30 (Box 83, Folder 899)
      - WNYC Phillip Lopate interview with Leonard Lopate American movie classics, undated (Box 83, Folder 900)
      - WNYC Phillip Lopate 62, undated (Box 83, Folder 901-902)
      - WNYC Phillip Lopate 92, undated (Box 83, Folder 903-905)
      - YCALMSS1083_0001, undated (Box 83, Folder 906)
      - unidentified cassette tapes, undated (Box 83, Folder 907-912)
    - Film reels
      - Bali one, undated (Box 83, Folder 913)
      - Bali two, undated (Box 83, Folder 914)
      - Black and white Central Park, undated (Box 83, Folder 915)
      - Larly's 50th anniversary, 1960-08-08 (Box 83, Folder 916)
      - Phillip Today Show, undated (Box 83, Folder 917)
      - PS 18 Phillip Lopate poetry, erased: PS 18 poetry lesson Phillip Lopate edited 460 feet, 1971-05-19 (Box 83, Folder 918)
    - Videocassettes
      - The Casserole Dish film by Phillip Lopate with Bill and Phyllis Zavatskey, photographed by Rudy Burckhardt, undated (Box 83, Folder 919)
      - Cheryl and Phillip's New Year's Eve Renaissance Rites on 19th Street, 1990-1991 (Box 83, Folder 920)
      - Cinema Then/Cinema Now "Il Bidone", undated (Box 83, Folder 921)
      - Cinema Then/Cinema Now "The Blue Angel" intro and outtro, undated (Box 83, Folder 922)
      - City Cinematheque into/discussion with Phillip Lopate "Take Care of My Cat", undated (Box 83, Folder 923)
      - IDCA Lopate talk: Hollywood Looks at the Movies", undated (Box 83, Folder 924)
      - Metro learning metro weekend, 1999-03-12 (Box 83, Folder 925)
      - National Geographic segments, Kevin Huffman 18th floor/The Pulse, 1211 Avenue of the Americas NY 10036, undated (Box 83, Folder 926)
      - Phillip Lopate at Queens College, undated (Box 83, Folder 927)
      - Phillip Lopate T and W films, undated (Box 83, Folder 928)
      - Phillip on chapter five Artifice, Pavorotti, NYC scenes, Yiddish culture, Liza Sumay, Frank, save, undated (Box 83, Folder 929)
      - PS 75 super 8 transfers-Bros. Revenge Broken Vase, Dole Man, Heaven and Hell, undated (Box 83, Folder 930)
      - Rick Winston and Phillip Lopate 78 minutes, undated (Box 83, Folder 931)
      - Uncle Vanya PS 75 at Symphony Space Theatre, 1979 (Box 83, Folder 932)
      - The Writer's Voice 10th Anniversary Season presents A Poet's Bible featuring David Bradley, E.M. Broner, Ann Lauterback, Phillip Lopate, Hugh Nissenson, Grace Schulman, David Shapiro, David Rosenberg, 1991-11-21 (Box 83, Folder 933)
      - 13 is My Lucky Number chapter 13 Video is Child's Play, undated (Box 83, Folder 934)